<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Operations on Portfolio / Christian Fuller</title><link>https://portfolio.christianf.io/operations/</link><description>Recent content in Operations on Portfolio / Christian Fuller</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://portfolio.christianf.io/operations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HPC operations and shell scripting</title><link>https://portfolio.christianf.io/operations/hpc-operations-shell-scripting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://portfolio.christianf.io/operations/hpc-operations-shell-scripting/</guid><description>&lt;p>These sample scripts represent two aspects of the work that I did as a developer in an HPC setting: environment configuration and job orchestration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I developed these scripts from scratch, using this as an opportunity to practice designing the deployment architecture for an HPC-based project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In researching to develop these samples, I taught myself how to work with Slurm and Python virtual environments, and dug into university HPC documentation to understand how virtual environments would work in a distributed context.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automated testing and deployment</title><link>https://portfolio.christianf.io/operations/automated-testing-deployment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://portfolio.christianf.io/operations/automated-testing-deployment/</guid><description>&lt;p>In my previous role, one of my responsibilities was managing the deployment of updates to my primary software project.
I managed the deployment of code changes that I wrote myself, and coordinated with teammates to get their changes merged in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After leaving that role, I was interested in learning modern tools and techniques for handling this process.
I taught myself GitHub Actions and developed a CI/CD pipeline that tests and deploys the site as changes are made.
I also used this as an opportunity to get more hands-on experience with GitHub&amp;rsquo;s pull request workflow by implementing CI tests for every merge into main.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>